Alice was beginning to get very tired of sitting by her sister on the bank, and of having nothing to do:
爱丽丝开始感到非常厌倦，坐在河岸边她姐姐身旁，无所事事：
once or twice she had peeped into the book her sister was reading, but it had no pictures or conversations in it,
她一两次偷偷瞥了一眼姐姐正在读的书，但书里既没有图画也没有对话，
So she was considering in her own mind (as well as she could, for the hot day made her feel very sleepy and stupid),
于是她在心里琢磨着（尽管炎热的天气让她感到昏昏欲睡且迟钝），
whether the pleasure of making a daisy-chain would be worth the trouble of getting up and picking the daisies,
编织一个雏菊花环的乐趣是否值得她起身去摘那些雏菊，
when suddenly a White Rabbit with pink eyes ran close by her.
就在这时，一只粉红眼睛的白兔突然从她身边跑过。
There was nothing so _very_ remarkable in that;
这并没有什么特别值得注意的；
(when she thought it over afterwards, it occurred to her that she ought to have wondered at this,
（事后回想起来，她觉得当时应该对此感到惊讶，
but at the time it all seemed quite natural); but when the Rabbit actually _took a watch out of its waistcoat-pocket_,
但当时这一切似乎都很自然）；然而，当兔子真的从背心口袋里掏出一块表，
and looked at it, and then hurried on, Alice started to her feet,
看了看，然后匆匆离开时，爱丽丝猛地站了起来，
for it flashed across her mind that she had never before seen a rabbit with either a waistcoat-pocket,
因为她突然想到，她从未见过有背心口袋的兔子，
or a watch to take out of it, and burning with curiosity, she ran across the field after it,
或者拿出一块表，她满怀好奇地跑过田野追赶它，
and fortunately was just in time to see it pop down a large rabbit-hole under the hedge.
幸运的是，她刚好及时看到它钻进篱笆下的大兔子洞里。
In another moment down went Alice after it, never once considering how in the world she was to get out again.
转眼间，爱丽丝也跟着钻了进去，完全没有考虑如何再出来。
The rabbit-hole went straight on like a tunnel for some way, and then dipped suddenly down,
兔子洞像隧道一样笔直延伸了一段，然后突然向下倾斜，
so suddenly that Alice had not a moment to think about stopping herself before she found herself falling down a very deep well.
倾斜得如此突然，以至于爱丽丝还没来得及思考如何停下来，就发现自己正坠入一个很深的井里。
Either the well was very deep, or she fell very slowly,
要么是井很深，要么是她下落得很慢，
for she had plenty of time as she went down to look about her and to wonder what was going to happen next.
因为她有充足的时间在下落时四处张望，并思考接下来会发生什么。
First, she tried to look down and make out what she was coming to, but it was too dark to see anything;
首先，她试图向下看，想弄清楚自己会落到哪里，但那里太黑了，什么也看不见；
then she looked at the sides of the well, and noticed that they were filled with cupboards and book-shelves;
然后她看了看井壁，发现上面满是橱柜和书架；
here and there she saw maps and pictures hung upon pegs.
她还看到到处挂着地图和画作，挂在钉子上。
She took down a jar from one of the shelves as she passed; it was labelled “ORANGE MARMALADE”,
她经过时从架子上取下一个罐子，上面标着“橘子酱”，
but to her great disappointment it was empty: she did not like to drop the jar for fear of killing somebody underneath,
但令她大失所望的是，罐子是空的：她不想扔掉罐子，怕砸到下面的人，
so managed to put it into one of the cupboards as she fell past it. ”
所以她在经过时设法把它放进了其中一个橱柜里。
thought Alice to herself, “after such a fall as this, I shall think nothing of tumbling down stairs.
爱丽丝心想，“经过这次跌落，我觉得从楼梯上滚下来也没什么大不了的。”
How brave they’ll all think me at home.
“在家的时候，他们一定会觉得我非常勇敢。”
Why, I wouldn’t say anything about it, even if I fell off the top of the house. ” (Which was very likely true. )
“哎呀，我什么都不会说的，就算我从屋顶上掉下来。”（这很可能是真的。）
Down, down, down. Would the fall _never_ come to an end. “I wonder how many miles I’ve fallen by this time. ”
往下，往下，再往下。这坠落难道永远不会结束吗？“我想知道现在我已经掉了多少英里了。”
she said aloud. “I must be getting somewhere near the centre of the earth.
她大声说道。“我一定快接近地球的中心了。”
Let me see: that would be four thousand miles down, I think— ” (for, you see,
“让我想想：那应该是四千英里深，我想——”（因为，你看，
Alice had learnt several things of this sort in her lessons in the schoolroom,
爱丽丝在学校教室里学过一些这类的东西，
and though this was not a _very_ good opportunity for showing off her knowledge, as there was no one to listen to her,
虽然这不是一个展示她知识的好机会，因为没有人听她说话，
still it was good practice to say it over) “— yes, that’s about the right distance—
但重复一遍还是很好的练习）“——是的，这大概是正确的距离——
but then I wonder what Latitude or Longitude I’ve got to. ”
但我不知道我现在是在什么纬度或经度。”
(Alice had no idea what Latitude was, or Longitude either, but thought they were nice grand words to say.
（爱丽丝根本不知道什么是纬度，也不知道什么是经度，但她觉得这些词说起来很气派。）